<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hallotron Harbor</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/</link><description>Recent content on Hallotron Harbor</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.hallotron.fyi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Elevators part 2</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/elevators2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 15:48:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/elevators2/</guid><description>code on github
This week I&amp;rsquo;ve been to NYC, and among seeing nice sights I&amp;rsquo;ve visited some skyscrappers. One of those was &amp;ldquo;Top of the Rock&amp;rdquo; which actually was the tallest skyscrapper in Rockerfeller center. It was nice, and here are the plots of the descent in the elevator (tried to capture the ascention but missed it unfortunatelly).
-7m/s Yikes, that&amp;rsquo;s fast. Besides - look at that S curve ! It&amp;rsquo;s almost like.</description></item><item><title>September Pictures</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/pictures/september/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 05:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/pictures/september/</guid><description> Your browser does not support the video tag.</description></item><item><title>GpsAnalisys</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/gpsanalisys/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 19:40:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/gpsanalisys/</guid><description>This one, I genuinely vibe coded in 10 minutes..
code</description></item><item><title>September Vacation</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/september-vacation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:29:42 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/september-vacation/</guid><description>First listen to this song and keep in mind, this is my mood throughtout this shitty story
So, Ryanair We had a planned flight at 20:40 of local time. A plane landing in Cracow skidded(?) of the runway and fell into the green parts of the airport around 15:20 that day.
Because of that there were massive crowds at the airport and none of the scheduled flights were taking off. Neither was ours.</description></item><item><title>BgRemover Part 2</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/bgremover-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 17:49:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/bgremover-part-2/</guid><description>Check out the previous post.
work done until now code on github
The original list(s):
nice-ish working front to be able to upload/download files actual background removal mechanix, but since it&amp;rsquo;s python this should be doable host it somewhere in my infra for it to be usable Nice to have-s:
instead of uploading an image pass a URL self-managed-file-deleting back-end option to select which model is used for the bgRemoval publically available on github to finally give back to community!</description></item><item><title>Elevators</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/elevators/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 19:26:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/elevators/</guid><description>code on github
This week I learned about a new app for Androids: phyPhox. It was shown to me by a friend from work. It was in a context of measuring the speed of elevators in buildings&amp;hellip; First things first - it allows to measure and log values from phones sensors - pressure, accelerometer, gyro, magnetometers, GPS, sound (amplitude, frequency). It&amp;rsquo;s a quite well written app. So, I have a super slow elevator in my building, where I live.</description></item><item><title>Rox</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/rox/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 19:03:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/rox/</guid><description>There is a bucket in my life. Not a bucket list, not a real bucket.
A metaphor of a bucket.
A place from which I feel like I draw my power. To do things, to be productive, &amp;ldquo;To strive, to seek, to find, and not to yield&amp;rdquo;.
There&amp;#39;s a secret place I like to go -Megadeth, Month before my birthday It&amp;rsquo;s a space, in which I find the willpower to run my life and do fun, impressive, good stuff.</description></item><item><title>First Photos With Apsc</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/first-photos-with-apsc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:46:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/first-photos-with-apsc/</guid><description>On the weekend of 21-23.08.2025 I went to my home, where I took some photos with my new camera.
I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say these are the best photos in the world, and I still have to learn a lot.. Yet still, I&amp;rsquo;m happy with them!</description></item><item><title>BgRemover</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/bgremover/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 20:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/bgremover/</guid><description>So uh, I kind of like to use background removers like remove.bg.. However there is an issue with them&amp;hellip;
They offer limited resolution of the output image and try charging like ~1$ per full image resolution inference&amp;hellip;
That seems un-cheap and I have the knowledge (insert Tai Lopez meme here) to build something like that for myself from ~scratch.
I recently adore NiceGUI for my projects and since this seems like a perfect use case I decided to go for it.</description></item><item><title>First pictures</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/pictures/first-pictures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 20:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/pictures/first-pictures/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thev Log</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/thev-log/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 19:57:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/thev-log/</guid><description>Creating this blog is kind of a fun part for me. Partly I hate it, but partly it&amp;rsquo;s a ready-made solution which requires proper configuration and a reasonable time spent to make it work. It&amp;rsquo;s mildly infuriating until you actually try to deploy it in a reasonable place like github pages. At that point it becomes simply unbearable.
It&amp;rsquo;s exactly like this, but I&amp;rsquo;m 3780 % more pissed than I should be 😅&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 19:44:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hallotron.fyi/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Post number 1 At this point in time, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get through installation of Hugo blog system&amp;hellip; somewhere in my infrastructure&amp;hellip; :]</description></item></channel></rss>